SOFTWARE QA ENGINEER

Profile

Oracle Database Administrator - Position that invite technical challenges in Database Design and Administration Experience in database administration and development of application software under Oracle, SQL server environments Performance tuning, database refresh, and day-to-day database monitoring activities Created roles, Privileges and assigned roles to users. Used Explain Plan to monitor execution path Used utilities like SQL Profiler, SQL Query Analyzer, SVRMGRL, Oracle Database Assistance, Oracle Enterprise Manager, and TKPROF for monitoring database performance Performed database backup and recovery, Mirroring Redo log, Hot, Cold, EXP/IMP Created tables in database with integrity constraints Install, configure and maintain software applications, operating systems and network monitoring Core Qualifications

- UNIX and Windows system administration including update kernels, install patches
- Extensive experience in both UNIX and Oracle administration
- Experience in Oracle replication technologies such as Shareplex replication, Advanced Replication, Data Guard, Oracle Streams and Golden Gate
- Extensive experience of UNIX, Shell scripting, writing stored procedures, triggers using PL/SQL
- Experience with Oracle 12c Multi-tenant, in-memory and Partitioning options in 12c HP-UX, IBM AIX, Linux RHEL, Linux CentOS, Sun Solaris, Windows, DOS
- Databases: Oracle 12c/11g/10g/9i, SQL Server 2000/2005/2012
- Tuning/Monitoring: RAC 12c/, RAC11R1/R2, RAC 10gR2, Data-Guard 9i/10g/11g, DB Cloning, Standby Databases, RMAN, SharePlex Replication
- Tools/Utilities: RMAN, OEM, SQL*Loader, SQL Server, Export/Import, TOAD, Data pump, Query builder, Net Backup, VB, Crystal Report, MS Access, Oracle Streams, SQL*Plus, SQL* Loader
- Programming Others: SQL, PL/SQL, C, C++, UNIX Shell Scripting, PERL, Bourne
- Web Development: IIS 4.0, ASP, HTML, CGI, Java Script

Professional Experience

March 2000 to October 2015 Bickford Senior Living i1/4 Iowa City, IA

• Perform all Oracle DBMS Server and Database Administration activities Perform all Backup/Recover and preventative maintenance activities Perform Database support and Troubleshooting activities Work with the development & QA teams to perform SQL code reviews/database structure modification Implement and maintain database security (create and maintain users and roles, assign privileges) Setup Real Application Server environments on ASM, raw devices, cluster filesystem, NFS and OCFS Configuring Oracle clusterware, Veritas Storage Foundation and familiar with third party clusterware including Veritas Advance cluster, TruCluster, Sun Cluster, HP Service Guard and Oracle cluster Design test plans, scenarios, scripts, or procedures Test system modifications to prepare for implementation Develop testing programs that address areas like database impacts, software scenarios, regression testing, negative testing, error or bug retests, or usability Install, maintain, or use software testing programs Design or develop automated testing tools.

Software QA Engineer

November 1998 to March 2000 3D Systems il/4 Lawrenceburg, TN

 Leading team to responsible of releasing the ProIV product, an object-oriented 4GL development language and RDBMS running under Window NT, Unix, Open VMS and Mainframe Automate the testing process through the use of automated testing tool (Rational SQA TeamTest) Develop test programs or scripts in the development of automated test procedures Visit beta testing sites to evaluate software performance Identify program deviance from standards, and suggest modifications to make sure compliance.

Software QA Engineer

November 1997 to November 1998 3D Systems il/4 Philadelphia, PA

• Responsible of testing a CSI's User Configurable Open System, a real time distributed control application Design and develop automated test procedures Perform software integration, system test and quality test function Develop and document test utilities, test programs and test scripts (Rational Visual Test) Document software defects, using a bug tracking system, and report defects to software developers.

Education

B.S. Degree: Electronic/Computer Engineering Cal Poly Pomona University Electronic/Computer Engineering Database Internals, Replication Internals, Database Administration, Backup - Recovery, Tuning, Advanced Symmetric Replication, Oracle Webserver Administration, Developing Web Applications with PL/SQL, Distributed Database Administration, Introduction to Data Warehousing, Implementing an Oracle Data Warehouse, New Features for Administrators, New Features for Developers, Managing Teamwork

4GL, IBM AIX, ASM, ASP, Automate, Backup, C, C++, CGI, Crystal Report, Data Warehouse, Database Administration, Databases, Database, DBMS, Data Warehousing, DOS, Features, HP, HP-UX, HTML, IIS 4, Java Script, Linux, Mainframe, Managing, memory, MS Access, SQL Server 2000, Windows, Window NT, NFS, object-oriented, Open VMS, Operating Systems, Oracle replication, Oracle Webserver, Oracle, DB, PL/SQL, PERL, ProIV, Programming, quality, QA, RDBMS, real time, scripts, Shell scripting, software developers, software testing, Sun Solaris, SQL, SQL Server, SQL*Loader, SQL* Loader, Sun, system administration, Teamwork, TOAD, Troubleshooting, UNIX, UNIX Shell Scripting, Utilities, Veritas, VB, Web Applications, Web Development